

Tiago Carreira DevOps Engineer

- Rio de Janeiro, Brazil
- © +55 21 98303-3680
- ▼ tiago.g.carreira.br@gmail.com
- inkedin.com/in/tcarreira
- github.com/tcarreira

# Soft Skills

- Productivity passionate
- Fast learner
- Highly adaptable
- Proactive and autonomous
- Good communicator
- Friendly and team player

# Technical Skills

























# **Technological Values**











Community driven

# **Personal Interests**







Podcasts. Audiobooks

Activeness, Achievement

Learning, Improving

# Languages

Portuguese



# English



Spanish



French

0000

Having ~8 years of experience with DevOps, I'm experienced with modern technologies (eg: Docker), proficient with Linux systems and many DevOps tools (eg. git, CI/CD, monitoring) and I'm confident developing in Python and Go.

Passionate about Linux, Open Source and productivity (I love scripting and automation). No person should be a single point of failure - procedures should be documented and/or automated.

I'm looking towards working with **smart people**, with whom I could learn and help learning; where **autonomy** is a valuable asset and **improving** is more important than finding who made a mistake.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### DevOps Engineer @ Globo.com

Specialist (via Globo) - July 2021 - Present (3 months) Prio de Janeiro, Brazil Senior (via Stormgroup) - August 2020 - June (11 months) PRio de Janeiro, Brazil

- Designed / improved CI/CD Pipelines, using Gitlab-CI and Docker
- Improved reliability for an API Gateway (Kong), serving 10K requests/s
- Programed and patch different code stacks (bash, Go, python, Lua, etc...)
- Provided support for multiple heterogeneous services across the company

## DevOps/Operations Engineer @ SAPO (BOLD by devoteam)

July 2017 - December 2019 (2 years 6 months) PLisbon, Portugal

- Implemented a monitoring stack with High Availability, using Grafana + Prometheus + Thanos (solely)
- Developed a Python/Django RESTful API for SSL Cert management (solely from scratch to production)
- DevOps advocate: improving Continuous Integration and best practices among the organization
- Data Center migration: bare metal, VM's, networking, data and storage (ensuring no downtime)
- Maintaining 500+ servers (using Puppet), 100+ services, both legacy and modern systems, on-call 24/7
- Solving internal operational tickets: forensics, bugs detection, infrastructure management

#### **DevOps Engineer @ Premium Minds**

December 2013 - June 2017 (3 years 7 months) PLisbon, Portugal

- Migrated on-premises infrastructure to AWS (EC2, RDS, VPC, ...)
- Infrastructure as code with python/boto3
- Defined the infrastructure and deployment pipeline for a High Available service on AWS telpark.com
- Managing Continuous Integration using Jenkins and Puppet

## **EDUCATION**

# MSc. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Instituto Superior Técnico | 2007 - 2013 P Lisbon, Portugal

- Major / Minor: Robotics & Control Systems / Computers
- Principal subjects: Database management, Objects Oriented Programming, Robotics
- Thesis: Quadcopter/Drone Automatic Take Off / Landing on a (mobile) Docking Station

#### Associate Cloud Engineer

Google Cloud | Sep 2021

• <u>credential.net/c880f8ea-7724-4ad4-9ad9-cf3e3f79fc28</u>

## Training & Courses

- May 2020 NDG Linux I/II course @ Cisco Networking Academy Essential System Services, Networking Fundamentals, Scripting, Administrative Tasks, Security
- Jan 2019 LPI DevOps Tools Engineer @ Linux Academy Config management, Cloud, RESTful APIs, Microservices, CI/CD, Security, Monitoring

## OTHER TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE & PROJECTS

2021 - TreeTree2: computer architecture I - github.com/tcarreira/nand2tetris-autograder

2020 - Podcasting (host, audio editor, web developer, designer) - github.com/marmita-de-redon Dashboard website project using Golang - github.com/tcarreira/roaw2020 REST API project using Python/Django - <a href="mailto:github.com/tcarreira/jogging-tracker">github.com/tcarreira/jogging-tracker</a> REST API project using Golang - github.com/tcarreira/superhero

2019 - Speaker @ Pyjamas Conf 2019 (Django on Docker) - github.com/tcarreira/django-docker Speaker @ Ubucon Europe 2019 (Docker) - tcarreira.github.io/presentations Volunteer (technical) @ Ubucon Europe 2019 - github.com/ubuconeurope

2018 - TreeTree2: HAC - Hacking the learn process on math/physics/programming with 10-16yo people

# PERSONAL ENDEAVORS

Sports: running (marathon), cycling (Lisbon-Santiago 600+ Km), obstacle course racing Music: clarinet, transverse flute, guitar, piano

Music groups: company's band, TUIST.tecnico.ulisboa.pt, multiple choirs, philharmonic orchestra Video production: youtube.carreira.pw, youtu.be/IKvtB-vNOek

Podcasting: marmita.pt (github.com/Marmita-de-Redon)

Personal skills: therapeutic massage (advanced integrated therapeutic massage course) Maker: Arduino, Raspberry Pi